JUSTIN HENRY FLORES

CONTACT

Phone: (951) 500-3676

Email: Justin.H.Flo@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Intermediate with Python, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, React, Java, Node.js, Django, PHP, MySQL, SQL, SQLite, Git, JSON and R
- Clear Understanding of REST API, Cloud Native Practices, DevOps, CI/CD, Containers, Docker, Kubernetes, Openshift, Microservices, Relational Database Concepts, and Serverless Computing.
- Novice with JQuery and XML
- Proficient with Tableau, Power BI, and Looker
- Advanced with Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word, Powerpoint, etc.)
- Advanced Analytical and Problem Solving Skills
- Efficient and Good Time Management
- Fast Learner
- Excellent Verbal and Written Communication
- Proficient with GitHub, Zoom,

WEBSITE

https://justin-h-flo.github.io/Website

CERTIFICATES

IBM Full Stack Software Developer

https://coursera.org/share/b9de1c4c16106ec9a01f11803e5fd021

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

https://www.credly.com/badges/d4ef2634-36b5-43f8-af4a-9ad12ca41118/public url

Python for Everybody

https://coursera.org/share/11ec97dfe5bbf130b0beaaf64db468cd

Java as a Second Language

https://coursera.org/share/e88132a91ae3ce6028294c5c1fc8494f

Agile with Atlassian Jira

https://coursera.org/share/23efccae58f1fe756ae48cb82bc619c3

Wharton's Business Analytics Specialization

https://coursera.org/share/7bc912b714cd889f366ccce81c6f3a20

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

My MacReu research internship was a paid summer internship that was funded by a National Science Foundation (NSF) award. I had the opportunity to work full time for 10 weeks on a research project. All of the students had the chance to do team building exercises which allowed us to develop our interpersonal skills. I also had the chance to present my work at the North American Solid State Chemistry Conference.

PUBLICATIONS

Ortner, T. S., Scheifers, J. P., Flores, J., Zhang, Y., Iyer, A. K.,

Slack, Agile, Jira, Scrum, and Kanban

- Self Starter
- Clear Understanding of Regression Analysis and A/B Testing

Gesing, T. M., & Fokwa, B. P. (2019). An old dog with new tricks – additions to the cesium lithium chloride system: Cs3Li2Cl5 and the hydrated Cs3LiCl4·4H2O. European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry, 2019(30), 3526–3535. https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.201900774

Scheifers, J. P., Flores, J. H., Janka, O., Pöttgen, R., & Fokwa, B. P. (2022). Triangular arrangement of ferromagnetic iron chains in the high-Tc ferromagnet TiFe1–xOs2+xB2. Chemistry – A European Journal, 28(42). https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202201058

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts: Neuroscience **University of California, Riverside** - Riverside, CA

WORK HISTORY

Delivery Driver, 06/2020 to Current **Doordash**

- Communicated customer complaints, requests and feedback to company management for swift resolution.
- Fostered positive working relationships with regular customers.
- Completed rush deliveries on tight timetables to satisfy customer needs.

Researcher, 10/2021 to 05/2022 University Of California, Riverside - Riverside, CA

- Collaborated with colleagues on a scientific publication.
- Conducted research into topics to provide valuable contributions.
- Interpreted and analyzed research data to draw conclusions on outcomes.
- Presented complex scientific topics in an understandable manner.

Research Assistant, 07/2018 to 03/2020 University Of California, Riverside - Riverside, CA

- Proficient with working in a glove box with a nitrogen atmosphere while performing exceptional synthetic work with chemicals. As well as sealing quartz tubes with a torch.
- Collaborated with colleagues on a scientific publication.
- Analyzed powder and single crystal X-ray diffraction data.